# **Tom Eagle**

119 Queens Road, Chester, CH3 5HF 01244 556515 07941 939374 tomeagle79@gmail.com http://www.renewingmycareer.wordpress.com

# **Personal Profile**

Mature Mechanical Engineering Graduate with 7 years proven capabilities in successfully managing own property services business and experience of consistently providing excellent customer service, delivering projects on time and on budget.

Possesses advanced problem-solving and fault finding skills, allied to sound practical judgement and has a track record of effectively working in the field. Has an affinity with IT and other technology and excellent numeracy and literacy, enabling effective and efficient record keeping and administration.

### **Qualifications**

- 1st class honours Mechanical Engineering UMIST (2000)
- A levels Maths (A), Physics (A), Gen Studies(A), Geography (C) 1997

# **Employment History**

### **Project assistant EcoVert Solutions Oct 2012 to present**

Working to provide greater energy efficiency and comfort levels in heritage buildings using appropriate materials for the age and structure of the property, whilst reducing carbon footprint and environmental impact.

### National Trust Volunteer (Wales environment team) March 2012 - present

I am an environment volunteer, working with the EPA's (environmental practise advisors) in Wales. The team is responsible for reducing the environmental impact of the organisation's properties and delivering renewable energy solutions where practical and appropriate. They are also involved in the development of community power generation schemes, something that I am keen to pursue. See <a href="http://ntenvironmentalwork.net/about/">http://ntenvironmentalwork.net/about/</a> for more info.

### Owner/Manager, Eagle Property Services – Chester April 2005 – Present

Responsible for managing and carrying out property maintenance/development contracts. These range from minor repairs and mechanical/electrical installations to full property refurbishment valued up to £55,000. Services provided include kitchen and bathroom renovation, plumbing and mechanical, electrical work, joinery.

Event crew member, Xtra Mile Events Ltd (triathlon events), April 2011 – October 2011

Assistant manager, Affinity Gardens landscaping, Chester, Spring 2003 - 2005

# **Accomplishments**

### **Eagle Property Services**

- Set up own property maintenance company and managed contracts for property renovations valued up to £55,000, which has been running successfully for 6 years.
  Managed to maintain business through difficult times in the construction industry.
- Sourced, planned and coordinated groups of trades people to fully meet the project criteria.
- Learned and used MS FrontPage software to create a website to promote property company.
- Achieved certification under BS7671: requirements for electrical installations.

### **Teaching/tutoring**

- Coached several secondary school pupils to successful GCSE and A level results.
- Taught GCSE science to secondary school pupils as part of PGCE course.

### **Affinity gardens**

 Managed staff, resources and equipment to provide high quality bespoke landscaping solutions to homes in the Chester area. Promoted from labourer to assistant manager.

#### **Trefn fabrications**

- Reduced waste in manufacturing of aircraft components by utilising AutoCAD in nesting of sheet metal components.
- Implemented tool cataloguing system to improve manufacturing efficiency in aircraft component factory.

#### University

- Achieved first class honours degree in Mechanical Engineering from one of UK's premier institutions Award for outstanding results in fluid mechanics and thermodynamics at University (> 90% pass rate).
- Used word processing and spreadsheet software packages to produce many technical reports to a high standard.
- Learned programming language from scratch to develop material testing equipment for university dissertation.

### **Core competencies**

- High level of numeracy, have achieved 95 percentile in competency tests.
- Tendering skills through providing quotes for customers of property business.
- Excellent practical skills such as wiring/plumbing/joinery. Quick to pick up new hands on skills.
- IT skills: proficient user of MS office programs. Experience with AutoCAD and programming languages (C and HTML). Able to learn and apply new software packages and technologies quickly and effectively.
- Problem solving and fault diagnosis in a bicycle business and on personal vehicles.
- Teaching and presentation skills.